<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Coding Challlenge 2.1</string>
    <string name="para_1">From far out in space, Earth looks like a blue ball. Since water covers three-fourths of the Earth’s
surface, blue is the color we see most. The continents look brown, like small islands floating in
the huge, blue sea. White clouds wrap around the Earth like a light blanket. The Earth is shaped
like a sphere, or a ball. It is 25,000 miles around! It would take more than a year to stroll around
the whole planet. A spaceship can fly around the widest part of the sphere in only 90 minutes.
Even though spaceships have traveled to the Moon, people cannot visit the Moon without special
suits. The Moon has no air or water. Plants and animals can’t live there either. Astronauts first
landed on the Moon in 1969. After that, there were six more trips to the Moon. They brought
back Moon rocks, which scientists are still studying. There are holes, or craters, all over the
Moon’s surface. Scientists believe that meteorites smashed into the Moon millions of years ago
and formed the craters.
The Sun is the closest star to Earth. A star is a hot ball of burning gas. The Sun looks very big
because it is so close. But the Sun is just a medium-sized star. Billions of far-away stars are
much bigger than our Sun. The burning gases from the Sun are so hot that they warm the Earth
from 93 million miles away! Even though the Sun is always glowing, the night here on Earth is
dark. That’s because the Earth rotates, or turns around, every 24 hours. During the day, the Earth
faces the Sun. Then we see light. During the night, the Earth turns away from the Sun. Then it
faces the darkness of space.
Each day we learn more about the Earth, the Moon, and the Sun.</string>


    <string name="para_2">The Delgado family had a new puppy named Lady. She was a playful puppy. She especially
liked playing with the garden hose. She loved to watch the hose wiggle like a snake when she
chewed on it. One day Mr. Delgado saw Lady drag the garden hose across the yard. “Not
again!” he said as he hung the hose on the hook that was on the side of the house.
 It was the fifth time this week that Lady had taken the hose down from its hook. Mr. Delgado
had tried to teach her not to do it. He pointed to the hose each time and said with a stern voice,
“No, Lady! Don’t play with the hose!” It hadn’t helped.
 The next day Mr. Delgado went outside to water his vegetable garden. Once again he found
the hose stretched across the yard. Lady playfully picked it up in her teeth when she saw him.
 Manuel came outside. “Hi, Dad,” he said. “May I help water the garden?” Manuel picked
up the hose, and Mr. Delgado turned on the water. Only a few drops of water fell on the plants.
They saw water springing up from tiny holes all along the hose.
 Manuel looked at Lady. “Your sharp teeth made those holes, Lady. You turned our hose into
a fountain,” he said. Lady wagged her tail proudly. Manuel and his father took the hose to the
garage. They used rubber glue to mend it. “I don’t know how to teach Lady to leave the hose
alone,” said Mr. Delgado once they had repaired the hose. “Do you have any ideas?”
 “I know what we can do,” said Manuel. He wrapped the hose around the hook again. Then he
brought two chairs from the yard. He turned them on their sides and leaned them against the
house. The chairs formed a cage around the hose.
 Lady walked over to the hose. She stuck her paw between the chairs. She poked the chairs
with her nose and cried. She tried and tried, but she couldn’t reach the hose. Manuel’s idea was
working. “You’re probably unhappy about this,” Manuel said to his puppy, “but Dad and I don’t
want to fix that hose every day!”</string>


    <string name="para_3">There are almost 400 different kinds of sharks. Each kind of shark looks different, has a unique diet,
and behaves differently. There are sharks in all four oceans of the world. Some sharks are longer than a
school bus, while others are so small they can live in fish tanks. Sharks come in all kinds of colors. Most
of the time, their skin color helps them blend in with their surroundings. But, some sharks that live in the
deepest part of the ocean actually have parts that glow in the dark. Most sharks live in salt water, but
some can live in fresh water. All sharks are unique, or have different qualities that make them so special.
 Sharks are actually a type of fish. There are some similarities as well as differences between sharks
and typical fish. Shark skeletons are made of cartilage. Fish skeletons are made of bones. Cartilage is
the bendy, tough substance in people’s ears and noses. Like other fish, sharks have gills. Gills are how
fish breathe. Unlike fish, people use lungs to get oxygen from the air. Fish get oxygen from the water
using gills. Water needs to move over the gills so that sharks and fish get enough oxygen. To keep the
water moving, most sharks need to swim in water that has a very strong current.
 Sharks have lots of teeth that are arranged in many rows, rather than in just one row like people. The
teeth from the outside row gradually fall out, and teeth from the next row take their place. Some sharks
will lose 30,000 teeth in a lifetime! Each species of shark has different kinds of teeth. This is because
different sharks eat different kinds of food. Some sharks eat food as small as plankton while other sharks
eat animals as big as sea turtles. Most sharks do not eat very often. Some sharks will go weeks between
meals. Sharks are at the top of the ocean food chain, which means that no animal is hunting them for
food. This position is very important because sharks keep the other animal populations from growing out
of control. This process helps ensure there is diversity, or many types, of life in the oceans.
 One of the things particularly special about sharks is they have been around a long time. Sharks have
lived in the oceans since dinosaurs roamed the Earth about 64 million years ago! Scientists believe there
may have even been shark relatives living 400 million years ago. Sometimes, sharks are described as
primitive because they have existed for so many years, and they have not changed much since then. It is
amazing how long sharks have been living in the ocean! Sharks are very different animals, and there are
many things people can learn about them.</string>


</resources>
